01

I'm Andy Hook, a designer & front-end developer based in Brighton.

Telephone 07980450299

Email hello@andy-hook.co.uk

Portfolio andy-hook.co.uk

LinkedIn linkedin.com/in/andyahook

Profile

Web professional with over 8 years of commercial design and development experience. Formally educated in fine art, digital design and illustration. I specialise in front-end and UI with a focus on scalable CSS architecture, modular JavaScript, systems driven design, interaction prototyping and browser performance.

Skills Digital Design

An expert Photoshop user with more than 10 years of experience working with the Adobe suite of creative applications. Extensive knowledge of web asset creation and image format optimisation. Experienced at all stages of the design process from problem definition and ideation through to wireframing, prototyping and delivery.

- Photoshop, Illustrator Production ready assets
- Framer, Invision Interaction prototyping and stakeholder collaboration
- Sketch Layout and design system distribution

Front-End Development

Detail orientated front-end developer experienced in delivering clean, well reasoned, modular and performant front-end code. I specialise in building scalable UI and design systems, sweating the details to ensure equal affordance to developer experience and design requirements.

- JavaScript ES6, React, Vue, Vuex, Nuxt, GSAP, Modernizr, JSON
- HTML5 Semantics, SEO, Accessibility, Wordpress, Node & Ruby SSG
- CSS3 SCSS/SASS, LESS, BEM, SMACSS, OOCSS, ITCSS, Atomic
- GIT, PHP, Webpack, Gulp, Grunt

н 02

Experience

Senior Front-End Developer

Brandwatch

July 2017 - May 2018

Specialised in front-end and UI design. Building, designing and mentoring on scalable CSS architecture, systems driven design, interaction, animation and browser performance. Ensured the team designed and implemented with a component driven mindset for future scalability and workflow cadence.

- Helped foster, cultivate and transform the web team into a high performing unit
- Developed CSS architecture to combine both atomic and semantic approaches
- Led design and development of digital content and page authoring toolkits

Web Designer

Brandwatch

April 2016 - July 2017

Worked within the commercial web team to overhaul the design and front-end of the core .com across multiple territories in 4+ languages. Collaborated closely with the product marketing team to launch a series of high profile product offerings.

Front-End Developer & Web Designer

The Jamieson Consultancy

January 2012 - January 2016

Led creative ideation, design and development projects including but not limited to; the implementation of modular pattern libraries, original site designs, email campaign automation, branding, identity. Provided mentorship to peers on code best practices.

Web Developer & Designer

Freelance – andy-hook.co.uk

July 2009 - January 2012

High quality graphic design, digital illustration and web development services.

Education

Bsc Honours Degree, Games Technology

The University of Portsmouth

September 2006 - July 2009

Foundation Diploma, Art and Design

Hastings College of Art and Technology

July 2005 - January 2006

National Diploma, Multimedia

Hastings College of Art and Technology

July 2003 - January 2005